Guide to the Historic Ephemera Collection 1880-2016
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Historic Ephemera Collection
1880-2016
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
SC 004
10 Linear feet of shelf space
This collection includes ephemeral materials, mainly printed items, on a wide variety of subjects, acquired from the mid-20th century onward from various sources.
Definition: Ephemera are "materials, usually printed documents, created for a specific, limited purpose, and generally designed to be discarded after use." (from A Glossary of Archival and Records Terminology by Richard Pearce-Moses). Pamphlets, admission tickets, performance programs, and trade cards are a few examples of ephemera.
This collection includes ephemeral materials, mainly printed items, on a wide variety of subjects, acquired from the mid-20th century onward from various sources.
The collection is arranged alphabetically by subject. In some cases, unsorted or miscellaneous items are filed at the end of each subject grouping.
This collection is open and available for research use.
The materials in this collection were received from many different sources, including old vertical files from the WSU Libraries and unaccessioned, unprocessed gifts. MASC staff gathered them into this collection, beginning in 2010.
This is an open-ended collection; additions are expected.
This collection includes only a small fraction of the ephemeral materials available in MASC. Many more items are included in manuscript collections, special collections, university archives, and the WSU Publications collection. Some ephemeral items held in MASC are individually cataloged, and can be found by searching the WSU Libraries' online catalog.
One of the larger ephemera collections held by MASC is the Washington State University Ephemera and Realia Collection, 1905- (SC 010)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Printed ephemera.
Media and Communication; Publishers and Publishing
- Agriculture
  - Crops
    - "The Palouse Country: The Home of Dry Edible Peas." Leaflet. Whitman County, WA.
    - Inland Empire Pea Growers Association, Inc. Fourteenth Annual Report. Oakesdale, WA, 1954 October 26.
  - Fruit box labels -- Washington State
    (Location note: fruit box labels are in Oversize 1)
    - "Shrader: Northwest Apples." E. E. Shrader and Co. Yakima.
    - "Empire Builder: Washington State Apples." Cashmere Pioneer Growers. Cashmere.
    - "Chere Best: Washington Apples." Columbia Fruit Packers, Inc. Wenatchee.
    - "Lake Chelan: Washington Boxed Apples." Lake Chelan Growers Union. Chelan. 2 copies.
    - "Trout Brand: Quality Boxed Apples." Lake Chelan Fruit Growers. Chelan.
    - "Hula Apples." Universal Fruit and Produce Co. Seattle.
    - "Dahn-D: Washington Apples." Floyd Dahn Fruits Inc. Wenatchee.
    - "Hi-Yu Brand Apples." Northern Fruit Co. Inc. Wenatchee.
    - "Blue Winner Brand." Okanogan Valley Apples. Okanogan Growers Union. Okanogan.
    - "Briskey Brand." Briskey and Sons. Naches.
    - “Red Winner: Okanogan Valley Apples.” Okanogan Growers Union. Okanogan.
      (Location note: Oversize 2)
    - Yakima Chief: Choice Evaporated Apples.” Washington Dehydrated Food Co. Yakima.
  - Gardening
    - Make the Garden Pay. L. A. Hawkins. International Harvester Company, 1926.
  - Livestock and Poultry
    - Yakima County Dairy Herd Improvement Association. Twenty-Fifth Annual Report, Silver Anniversary. 1926-1951.
    - Whitman County Fair and Horse Show. Premium List. 1952.
    - Vaccination as a Preventive Remedy Against Diseases of Live Stock. Harold Sorby. 1895.
    - Agriculture and Livestock in the Lewiston County. Lewiston Commercial Club. Lewiston, ID.
    - Washington Swine Breeders Directory 1955-56. Washington Swine Breeders Association. Pullman, WA.
    - "Washington: the Evergreen State in the Pacific Northwest, Supreme for Poultry." Pamphlet. Washington Record of Performance Breeders. Puyallup, WA. 1925.
    - "Weyerhaeuser Utility Products for Chicken Raisers." Brochure. Weyerhaeuser Timber Co. Everett, WA.
    - Fisher's Radio Visits with Pacific Northwest Poultrymen and Dairymen. Pamphlet. Fisher Flouring Mills Company. Seattle. Circa 1930.
    - Fifteenth Annual Report of the Whatcom County Dairy Herd Improvement Association. 1937.
    - Seventh Annual Report: Thurston County Dairy Herd Improvement Association. 1927-1928.
    - Washcoegg. Washington Co-operative Egg and Poultry Association Newsletter. Vol. 9, No. 43. 1932 April 2.
    - S.C. White Leghorns as bred at Tancred Farms. Tancred Breeding Farms Catalog. Kent, WA. Circa 1920s.
    - "Wilcox Farms Inc." Pamphlet. Roy, WA.
    - Eighteenth Annual Report of the Skagit and Island County Dairy Herd Improvement Association. 1940. 2 copies.
    - Nineteenth Annual Report of the Skagit and Island County Dairy Herd Improvement Association. 1941.
    - Pacific Northwest Brown Swiss Cattle Breeders' Directory. Pamphlet. Circa 1960.
    - Pacific Northwest 1963-64 Directory. Guernsey Breeders: Herd and Herd Sire Information.
    - "Cattle Thieves Beware: $500 Reward." Broadside. Washington Cattle Association. Ellensburg, WA.
    - Stock certificate and accompanying information. Washington Co-operative Egg and Poultry Association. 1928.
  - Livestock -- Cattle sale catalogs
    - Seventh Annual Draft of Hercules Shorthorns. Hercules Ranch, Sprague, WA. 1927 February 25.
    - Second Annual Thurston County Holstein Sale. Oakville, WA. 1925 June 10.
    - Pacific International Jersey Sale. North Portland, Oregon. 1923 November 8.
    - Pacific International Guernsey Sale. North Portland, Oregon. 1923 November 7.
    - Gue's Fall Consignment Sale of Registered Holstein-Friesians. Silver Lake Fairgrounds. 1926 October 20.
    - Pacific International Hereford Sale. Portland, Oregon. 1924 November 7.
    - Annual Pacific International Sale of Hereford Cattle. Portland, Oregon. 1926 November 5.
    - Northwest Holstein Breeders' Second Annual Pacific International Quality Holstein Sale. Portland, OR. 1927 November 4.
    - Complete Dispersal Sale. Satsop, WA. 1921 July 22.
    - Third Semi-Annual Sale. Western Washington Holstein Breeders' Association. Snohomish, WA. 1916 May 3-4.
    - Seventh Semi-Annual Sale. Western Washington Holstein Breeders Association. Kent, WA. 1918 April 17.
    - Grays Harbor County: Sale of Holstein-Friesian Cattle. Elma, WA. 1924 October 14.
    - Washington State Holstein Sale. Snohomish, WA. 1924 June 25.
    - Annual Pacific International Shorthorn Sale. Portland, OR. 1932 October 20.
    - Northwest Holstein Breeders' First Annual Pacific International Quality Holstein Sale. Portland, Oregon. 1926 November 5.
    - Riverland Holstein Complete Dispersal Sale. 1925 December 14.
    - Wood Creek Stock Farm Dispersal Sale. Monroe, WA. 1926 February 22.
    - Catalog of the Evergreen Dairy Classic 5th Annual Fall Sale, featuring Holstein-Friesian Cattle. Mount Vernon, WA. 1945 October 15.
    - Sacrifice Dispersion Sale. Coeur d'Alene, ID. 1945 December 11.
    - Sale of Registered Dairy Bulls. Oregon Agricultural College. 1921 June 16.
    - Lee Brothers Reduction Sale. Skagit County Fairgrounds, Mt. Vernon, WA. 1924 October 22.
    - First Annual Quality Guarantee Sale. Whatcom Co. Holstein-Friesian Breeders Association. Lynden, WA. 1922 May 11.
    - Announcing Dispersal Sale. Stanwood, WA. 1922 December 6.
    - Firloch Stock Farm Holstein Dispersal. Redmond, WA. 1928 August 31.
    - A Reduction Sale of Hamilton Holsteins. Chehalis, WA. 1925 June 24.
  - Victory gardens
    - Victory Garden Guide. New edition. Standard Oil Company of California, 1944.
  - Miscellaneous
    - Twenty-Third Annual Manufacturers' and Land Products Show and Seventeenth Annual Northwest Grain Show. Premium list, Pacific International Livestock Exposition, Inc. Portland, OR. 1938 October 1-9.
    - The Spokane County Farm Bureau News. Newsletter. Spokane. 1920. (Location note: oversize 2)
    - "Use Ford Nitrogen Plant Food." Brochure. Ford Motor Company. Dearborn, MI. Circa 1940s-1950s.
    - A Business Program for the Farm. Pamphlet. Washington State Agricultural Conservation Committee. Circa 1937.
    - Images of the Land: A Pictorial Journey through Washington Wheat Country. David Anderson. Wheat Life.
    - Tractor Motor Lubrication: A Hand-book for the Tractor Operator. Thomas E. Coleman. Madison, WI. Revised,1918.
  - Unsorted Items
- Alcohol
  - "Happy Hour Mixology: 44 Famous Mixed Drinks." Southern Comfort Corporation. St. Louis, MO. Circa 1970s.
- Artifacts (realia)
  (Location note: in Oversize 2)
  - "Peace and Friendship" medal (Jefferson peace medal). Replica, 105 mm. (Location note: on display in MASC reading room)
  - Dial-A-Matic Automatic Adding Machine. Sterling Plastics.
  - U and I Sugar Co. souvenir. Toppenish plant opening. Circa 1917.
  - Token for $.10 cup of coffee at any Sambo's Restaurant. 1972.
  - $ silver certificate.
  - Valentine's postcard from WWI, addressed to Carl Brewster, Jr. of Pullman, WA.
  - Miscellaneous
- Business
  - A Question every Business Woman asks Herself. New England Mutual Life Insurance Company. Boston, MA.
  - What Kind of America? Benjamin F. Fairless. Pamphlet. Circa 1953.
  - The Palmer Method of Business Writing. A. N. Palmer. The A. N. Palmer Company. 1926.
  - A B C's of Scapegoating. Pamphlet. Foreword by Professor Gordon W. Allport.
  - "State of Washington Motor Vehicle Financial Responsibility Law." Brochure. Aetna. 1939.
  - The March Through Life. First National Bank, Pullman, WA. 1919 July.
  - First National Bank and Trust Company card.
  - How to Sell Leather Goods in a Drug Store. Booklet. Amity Leather Products, Co. West Bend, WI. 1930.
- Calendars
  - 1944 calendar. New England Mutual Life Insurance Company.
  - July, August, and December 1957 calendars. Higgins Drug Store. Pullman, WA. (Location note: oversize 1).
  - Pullman: Glimpses of the Past. 1974 Calendar. Pullman Printers.
  - Kodol Almanac 200 year calendar. E.C. DeWitt & Co. Chicago. 1903.
- Cameras
  - "Flash Kodaguide" (calculator). Eastman Kodak Company.
  - "Outdoor Snapshots in Color." Booklet. Dufay Color Company. New York.
  - "Rainbow Hawk-Eye No. 2 Folding Model C, Single Lens." Eastman Kodak Company. Rochester, NY. Circa 1930s-1940s.
- Dams
  - Pacific Northwest -- Columbia Basin Project
    - "Welcome to...Rocky Reach Dam." Brochure.
    - "Fish Facilities on the Lower Columbia and Snake rivers at Corps of Engineers' Projects [Portland]." Brochure. Portland, OR. 1968.
    - "Lower Snake Project: Slack Water to Lewiston." Brochure. U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, Walla Walla District. 1973.
    - "Bonneville Dam: Oregon and Washington." Brochure. U.S. Army Engineer District, Portland. 1973.
    - "Dworshak: Dam and Reservoir." Brochure. Walla Walla District Corps of Engineers. Walla Walla, WA. 1973.
    - "Ice Harbor: Lock and Dam." Brochure. Snake River, WA. Walla Walla District Corps of Engineers.
    - "John Day Dam (Lake Umatilla): Oregon and Washington." Brochure. U.S. Army Engineer District, Portland. 1970.
    - "Ririe Dam and Lake." Brochure. U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, Walla Walla District. 1971.
    - "The Dalles Dam: Oregon and Washington." Brochure. U.S. Army Engineer District, Portland. 1973.
    - Grand Coulee Dam and the Columbia Basin Reclamation Project. Pamphlet. United States Department of the Interior, Bureau of Reclamation.
    - "Rocky Reach" Hydroelectric project of the Columbia River." Pamphlet. Chelan County Public Utility District. Wenatchee, WA.
    - Map of current and proposed dams on the Snake and Columbia Rivers.
    - Report on Water Resource Development, Columbia River Basin. Public hearing statement of Paul W. Light, Inland Navigation Company, before the Corps of Engineers, U.S. Army. Typescript (includes photographs). Portland, OR. 1959 March 11.
    - KSEM Columbia Basin Progress Edition. December, 1955. (Location note: in Oversize 2)
    - "John Day Lock and Damn (Columbia River): Oregon and Washington." Brochure. US Army Corps of Engineers, Walla Walla District. September, 1958.
    - "McNary Dam: Oregon and Washington." Pamphlet. US Army Corps of Engineers. Walla Walla District. Circa 1955.
  - Unsorted Items
- Education
  - Colleges and universities
    See also the Washington State University Ephemera and Realia Collection, 1905- (SC 010)
    - "Here We Have Idaho: A Self-guide to the University of Idaho." Brochure. Moscow, ID.
    - The News Letter of the College English Association. Union College: Schenectady, NY. Vol. 4, No. 7. 1942 November.
    - The News Letter of the College English Association. University of Maryland: College Park, MD. Vol. 8, No. 4. 1946 April.
    - The Asian Student. Orientation Handbook, Sixth edition. San Francisco, CA.
    - Washington State Normal School: Annual Catalog 1933-1934. Vol. 30. Bellingham, WA. 1933.
    - "Semi-Centennial Celebration: University of Washington." Program. Circa 1911.
    - The Funding Crisis in Washington: Public Universities: A Few Facts. Pamphlet. 1980.
    - Colleges and universities -- Library bookplates
      - Envelope 1
        - State Agricultural and Technical Institute. Canton, NY.
        - University of Idaho.
        - University of Illinois. 4 copies.
        - University of Maryland.
        - University of Georgia.
        - University of Massachusetts.
        - Miscellaneous bookplates.
        - Boyden Library. Foxboro, MA.
      - Envelope 2
        - University of Chicago.
      - Envelope 3
        - State College of Washington.
  - Correctional institutions
    - "Educational Opportunities of W.S.R." [Washington State Reformatory.] Leaflet. 1935 September 15.
    - "An Educational Survey of the Inmates of Washington State Reformatory." Department of Education leaflet. Monroe, WA. 1935.
  - High School
    - Cartoon Features For Progressive High School Publications. Student Publications Service, Illinois. 1942-1943.
    - "Where am I Going?" Washington Pre-College Test pamphlet. Circa 1973.
  - Languages
    - The Esperanto Home-Student. James Robbie. Eleventh edition. Washington, D.C. 1942.
    - Bokabulario: Esperanto=Ispano-Amerikano. Compiled by Jesus Amaya. 1934.
  - Rural Library Service
    - Rural Library Service. Farmers' Bulletin No. 1847. U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Agricultural Economics. 1940.
  - Schools
    - King County
      - "King County Schools." William J. Hutchins. Leaflet. Circa 1918.
      - "King County Schools." A.S. Burrows. Broadside. Circa 1918. (Location note: oversize 2)
      - "Good News for W. J. Hutchins. He Wins a $5,000 Prize." American Magazine, No. 85 (1918), 25-27. Photocopy. (Location note: oversize 2)
    - Lacrosse, WA
      - Lacrosse High School diploma for Helen Joyce Fleming, class of 1930.
    - Pullman, WA
      - "The Pullman High School Commencement Program." 1950 June 1.
      - "The Pullman High School Baccalaureate Services." 1950 May 28.
      - "Annual Report." Pullman School District No. 267. 1959-1960 School Year.
      - "Pullman Adult Education Opportunities." Pullman School District brochure. Spring 1974.
      - "Daycare." (Mimeographed proposal to set up nursery school-child care centers in Pullman schools). 1973.
    - Spokane, WA
      - Spokane Public School: Circular of Information. Pamphlet with information about teacher qualifications and compensation. Circa 1920s-1930s.
  - Science
    - The United States Atomic Energy Commission: What It Is, What It Does. Pamphlet. Revised edition, 1967.
    - Our Atomic World: The Story of Atomic Energy. C. Jackson Craven. Pamphlet. Revised edition, 1964.
    - The Mystery of Matter. William G. Pollard. United States Atomic Energy Commission Division of Technical Information pamphlet, 1970.
    - Nuclear Power and the Environment. United State Atomic Energy Commission Division of Technical Information pamphlet, 1969.
    - Radioactive Wastes. Charles H. Fox. Revised edition. United States Atomic Energy Commission Division of Technical Information pamphlet, 1969.
  - Study tips
    - Hints on How to Study. Phi Eta Sigma, 1946.
  - Teachers and Teaching
    - How To Apply For A Position and Why Teachers Fail. Pamphlet. North Central Teacher Service.
    - Teachers' Application Handbook. Schummer School Service. Seattle. 1938.
  - Technical Training
    - "Preliminary Instructions for Beginners in Telegraphy as taught by the Wenthe Railway Correspondence School, of Freeport, Ill., U.S.A." J.W. McCaffrey. Circa 1900-1910.
  - Unsorted Items
- Fish
  - "Dworshak National Fish Hatchery." Brochure. Ahsahka, ID. 1973.
  - The Story of Salmon. Isabel N. Young. Pamphlet. New York: American Can Company. 1934.
  - "Game Fish: Seasons and Limits, 1970." Pamphlet. [Washington] State Game Department.
- Forestry
  - Forestry in the Pacific Northwest. Hugo Winkenwerder. The American Tree Association, 1928.
- Home Economics
  - "Chevron Cleaning Solvent." Flyer. Standard Stations, Inc.
  - Hearing. Pamphlet. New York. Metropolitan Insurance Company.
  - First Aid. Pamphlet. New York Metropolitan Insurance Company.
  - Living the Healthy Life. Jesse Feiring Williams. Pamphlet. John Hancock Mutual Life Insurance Company. Boston, MA.
  - Epilepsy- the Ghost is Out of the Closet. Herbert Yahraes. Public Affairs Pamphlet No. 98.
  - When Our Parents Get Old. Pamphlet. Metropolitan Life Insurance Company.
  - Overweight and Underweight. Pamphlet. Metropolitan Life Insurance Company.
  - Soaps and Detergents. Pamphlet. Soap and Detergent Association. 1981.
  - The Art of Home Furnishing and Decoration. Frank Alvan Parsons. Armstrong Cork Company. 1918.
  - "About Fabrics and Patterns: No. 1: Lessons 1 and 2." Booklet. Singer Manufacturing Company. 1957.
  - "Pattern Layout Cutting and Marking: No. 2: Lesson 3." Booklet. Singer Manufacturing Company. 1957.
  - "Fitting -- Buttonholes and Pockets: No. 3: Lesson 4." Booklet. Singer Manufacturing Company. 1957.
  - "Bastings, Seams, and Slashes: No. 4: Lesson 5." Booklet. Singer Manufacturing Company. 1957.
  - "Seam Finishes, Neckline, and Joinings: No. 5: Lesson 6." Booklet. Singer Manufacturing Company. 1957.
  - "Sleeves, Plackets, and Closings: No. 6: Lesson 7." Booklet. Singer Manufacturing Company. 1957.
  - "Hems, Belts, and Finishes: No. 7: Lesson 8." Booklet. Singer Manufacturing Company. 1956.
  - Food
    - Good Things to Eat Made With Arm and Hammer Baking Soda. Martha Lee Anderson. Pamphlet. 1933.
    - Health Playmates. Ethel T. Wolverton. Leaflet. Wheat Flour Institute.
    - Blackboard Lessons on Food. Marguerite Breen and Agnes Larson. Pamphlet. Wheat Flour Institute. Chicago. 1937.
    - "Three Meals a Day." Pamphlet. Kellogg Company. 1928.
    - Planning Meals. Pamphlet. John Hancock Mutual Life Insurance Company. 1932.
    - Eskimo Cook Book. Pamphlet (2nd ed.). Prepared by students of Shishmaref Day School. Shishmaref, AK. Circa 1950s.
    - "The Oregon Trail." A worksheet for children to learn healthy eating habits and behavior (uncut sheet, 8 pages).
    - What Makes Jelly "Jell"? Pamphlet with recipes. General Foods Corporation. New York. 1951.
    - "Familiar Foods and Party Treats." Pamphlet. Seven-Up Co. St. Louis, MO. 1953.
    - Legume Your Menu: Cooking with Dry Peas and Lentils. Pamphlet. Washington and Idaho Pea and Lentil Commissions. Moscow, ID. Circa 1990.
    - Cinderella at the Race. Ethel T. Wolverton. Wheat Flour Institute. Chicago.
    - Rip Van Winkle's Health Sleep. Ethel T. Wolverton. Wheat Flour Institute. Chicago.
    - Canning Jar Labels. Booklet of labels. U and I Sugar. Circa 1940s-1950s.
  - Unsorted Items
- Health
  - Parents Guide to Marijuana. L. Robert McNally. Pamphlet. Circa 1970s (2 editions).
  - A Friend in Need. Church and Dwight Co., Inc. 1933.
  - "Facts." Ransom's Illustrated Encyclopedia. D. Ransom, Son & Co. Buffalo, NY. Circa 1880s-1890s.
  - Use of Chemical Additives in Foods. Booklet. Food Protection Committee, Food Nutrition Board. National Research Council. Washington, D.C. 1951.
  - The Prize Winner. Pamphlet on diphtheria. Circa 1930.
  - "Straight from the Shoulder." National Dairy Council. Chicago. 1945.
  - "Eugenics Seeks to Improve the Natural Qualities of the Human Family." The Eugenics Records Office. Long Island, NY. Circa 1920s.
  - Hygiene and Reproduction
    - So You Don't Want to be a Sex Object. Sheri S. Tepper. Pamphlet. 1977.
    - Look at Your Future. Pamphlet/Comic strip. American Institute of Men's and Boys' Wear, Inc. New York. 1962.
    - Manpower. United States Public Health Service. Washington, D.C.
    - When Abortion was Illegal: Untold Stories. Brochure with information on short film. Bullfrog Films. Oley, PA. Circa 1980s.
    - Women's Hygiene ads for Quest Deodorant Powder, Kurb tablets, and Kotex. Circa 1940s-1950s.
    - Prophylactics: sales literature. Penn Supply Company. 1935.
    - Prophylactics brochure and order form. Por-Tex Distributors. 1935.
    - Prophylactics and other sexual hygiene products: sales literature. Boswell Products. 1935.
    - Growing Up and Liking It. Booklet. Personal Products Corporation. Circa 1958.
    - Janie's Diary: All About Grooming for Early Teens. Booklet. Makers of Mum. New York. 1957.
    - Through the Looking Glass to Good Grooming. Booklet. Proctor & Gamble. 1956.
    - Beauty on a Budget. Booklet. The Gillette Co. 1955.
    - Beauty on a Budget. Booklet. The Gillette Co. 1957.
    - Hair Beauty on a Budget! Booklet. The Gillette Co. 1958.
    - How to Make your Figure Add Up...With Proper Bras and Girdles. Booklet. E.I. DuPont de Nemours and Co. Circa1950s.
    - "Glamour for Teens." Brochure. Hollywood V-Ette Vassarette. 1958.
    - Beauty Guides. Glynne. 3-ring binder inserts. Circa 1950s.
  - Unsorted Items
- Lewis and Clark Bicentennial Commemoration, 2001-2006
  - Newspaper clippings, 2001-2003
  - Book dust jackets
  - Miscellaneous materials, 2001-2006
- Military
  - Qualifying Test For Civilians. 9 November, 1943. Information about the qualifying test for the Army Specialized Training Program and the Navy College Program.
  - Mt. Rainier Ordnance Depot map and type-written description. Circa 1940s.
  - Insignia
    - "Insignia of the Army, Navy and Marine Corps." Brochure.
    - "How to Identify Them: Army and Navy." Blotter.
- National Symbols
  - Flag of the United States
    - The Stars and Stripes of the United States. Pamphlet. 1970.
- Organizations
  - American Legion
    - American Legion, Maynard-Price Post No. 52, Pullman, WA. Coasters.
    - American Legion programs. Department of Washington: Walla Walla and Bellingham. 1937-1938.
  - Clubs (see also Women's Clubs)
    - Constitution, By-Laws, Rules and Lists of Members of the University Club of Spokane. 1926 April 17.
    - Spokane Country Club. Pamphlet with constitution, by-laws, rules, directory, etc. 1919 and 1922.
    - Tuesday Evening Club. Colfax, WA. 1902-1908.
    - Xenodican Club. Palouse, WA. 1925-1926.
    - Narcissa Whitman Club Year Book. Asotin, WA. 1927-1928.
  - Grange (Patrons of Husbandry) -- National
    - "The Grange Initiate and Declaration of Purpose of the Order of Patrons of Husbandry." Pamphlet.
    - "Introducing the Grange." Flyer. The National Grange. Washington, D.C. 2 copies.
    - "Welcome to the Grange." Brochure. The National Grange Building. Washington, D.C. 2 copies.
    - "Grange Women." Flyer. The National Grange. Washington, D.C.
    - "What is the Grange?" Leaflet. The National Grange. Washington, D.C.
  - Grange (Patrons of Husbandry) -- Washington State
    - "The Junior Grange: An Organization for Rural Boys and Girls." Leaflet. Washington State Grange Junior Department. Seattle, WA. 2 copies.